Register of the Samuel Tankersley Williams papers, 1917-1980
Hoover Institution Archives
- MILITARY ASSISTANCE ADVISORY GROUP (MAAG), VIETNAM FILE, 1955-1960 (Boxes 12-16)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1960
    - Harris, Dick, Jr., 1958 (Box-folder 12: 36)
    - Harrold, Lt. Gen. Thomas L., 1958 (Box-folder 12: 37)
    - Hartshorn, Brig. Gen. Edwin S., Jr., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 12: 38)
    - Hilburn, Herbert, 1956 (Box-folder 12: 39)
    - Hill, Paul, 1958 (Box-folder 12: 40)
    - Horner, Col. Charles T., Jr., 1959 (Box-folder 12: 41)
    - Huebner, Lt. Gen. C. Ralph, 1960 (Box-folder 12: 42)
    - Jaegher, Father Raymond de, 1958 (Box-folder 12: 43)
    - Klein, Maj. Gen. John A., 1956 (Box-folder 12: 44)
    - Kroth, Fred, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 12: 45)
    - Krueger, Gen. Walter, 1956 (Box-folder 12: 46)
    - Lansdale, Edward G., 1959 (Box-folder 12: 47)
    - Lavergne, Daly C., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 12: 48)
    - Lawless, Lt. Col. Roger, 1959 (Box-folder 12: 49)
    - Le-Van-Kim, Gen., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 12: 50)
    - Le-Van-Ty, Lt. Gen., 1956 (Box-folder 12: 51)
    - Lindeman, Maj. Gen. Philip F., 1956 (Box-folder 12: 52)
    - Magruder, Lt. Gen. Carter B., 1956-1959 (Box-folder 12: 53)
    - Maroun, Autrey J., 1956 (Box-folder 12: 54)
    - Miller, George P., 1959 (Box-folder 12: 55)
    - Myers, Lt. Gen. Sam, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 12: 56)
    - Ngo-Dinh-Diem
      - Conferences, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 12: 57)
      - Conversations
        - 1957 (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
        - 1958 (Box-folder 13: 3-5)
        - 1959 (Box-folder 13: 6-7)
        - 1960 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
      - Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 14: 3)
      - Reports and recommendations, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Ngo-Dinh-Nhu, Mr. and Mrs., 1959 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Nilsson, Lt. Col. Erwin G., 1958 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - O'Daniel, Lt. Gen. John W., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Opal, Chester H., 1959 (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Paik, Lt. Gen. In Yup, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 14: 9)
    - Paik, Gen. Sun Yup, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 14: 10)
    - Pak, Brig. Gen. Chin Suk, 1958 (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - Palmer, Lt. Gen. Charles D., 1956 (Box-folder 14: 12)
    - Phinney, Maj. Gen. Carl L., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 14: 13)
    - Powell, Maj. Gen. Herbert B., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 14: 14)
    - Randolph, A. B., 1959 (Box-folder 14: 15)
    - Randolph, Mrs. A. Kenneth, 1958 (Box-folder 14: 16)
    - Rich, Brig. Gen. Charles W. G., 1956 (Box-folder 14: 17)
    - Riley, Vice Adm. Herbert D., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 14: 18)
    - Shin, Choi Duk, Ambassador, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 14: 19)
    - Shultz, Capt. John M., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 14: 20)
    - Song, Lt. Gen. Yo Chan, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 14: 21)
    - Spear, Mr. and Mrs. Eugene, 1958 (Box-folder 14: 22)
    - Stilwell, Col. Richard, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 14: 23)
    - Strickler, Gilbert E., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 14: 24)
    - Stump, Adm. Felix, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 14: 25)
    - Taylor, Brig. Gen. Benjamin F., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 14: 26)
    - Taylor, Gen. Maxwell D., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 14: 27)
    - Thai-Qang-Hoang, Maj. Gen., 1956 (Box-folder 14: 28)
    - Townsend, Elias C., 1956 (Box-folder 14: 29)
    - Tram-Ngoc-Tam, Brig. Gen., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 14: 30)
    - Tran-Trung-Dung, 1956 (Box-folder 14: 31)
    - Tran-Van-Don, Maj. Gen., 1956 (Box-folder 14: 32)
    - Tran-Van-Minh, Maj. Gen. (Little Minh), 1956 (Box-folder 14: 33)
    - Trudeau, Lt. Gen. Arthur, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 14: 34)
    - Van Fleet, Gen. James A., 1958 (Box-folder 14: 35)
    - Watts, Marvin, 1959 (Box-folder 14: 36)
    - Weible, Lt. Gen. Walter L., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 14: 37)
    - White, Gen. I. D., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 14: 38)
    - Williams, Ed P., Jr. (Samuel Williams' nephew), 1958 (Box-folder 14: 39)
    - Williams, Mr. and Mrs. Ed P., Sr. (Samuel Williams' brother), 1958 (Box-folder 14: 40)
    - Williams, Lt. Gen. Edward T., 1956 (Box-folder 14: 41)
    - Wong, William, 1958 (Box-folder 14: 42)
    - Wooten, Ben H., 1956 (Box-folder 14: 43)
  - Directories of government personnel, Republic of Vietnam
    - 1959 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - 1960 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Map (Box-folder 15: 3)
    Depicts probable attack plan of North Vietnam. Prepared by Gen. Tran Van Don.
  - Memoranda
    - General (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Evaluations of South Vietnamese military officers (Box-folder 15: 5-6)
    - Evaluations (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Reports
    - "Background Briefing on Indochina," Department of the Army, Office, Assistant Chief of Staff, G-2, Production Division, typescript, 1955 October (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - "Country Study," United States Department of Defense, printed copy, 1959 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - "The High Regions of Central Vietnam: Dalat and Lam Dong," from the office of the Director General for Security, typescript, 1958 July 31 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - Intelligence report on Dr. Phan Huy Quat (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - "Prominent Members Among the Governing Elite of the Republic of Vietnam," typescript, undated (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Speeches and writings
    - Speech list and notes (Box-folder 16: 7)
    - Untitled, typescript, circa 1958 (Box-folder 16: 8)
    - Speech, "Thoughts on the Infantry Division," typescript, circa 1958 (Box-folder 16: 9)
    - Speech, the World Veterans Federation, typescript, 1958 (Box-folder 16: 10)
    - Speech, PACOM Conference, typescript, 1958 January (Box-folder 16: 11)
    - Speech, presentation of the MacArthur Trophy, Vietnamese Military Academy, typescript, 1958 April 12 (Box-folder 16: 12)
    - Speech, "Effect of Geneva Accords on Map in Protocol States," PACOM-MAAG Chiefs' Conference, Okinawa, typescript, 1959 (Box-folder 16: 13)
    - Briefing, "Summary of MAAG-Term, Vietnam Situation and Activities," National War College, typescript, circa 1959 (Box-folder 16: 14)
    - Briefing, "CIT Intelligence," Senior Advisor's Conference, typescript, 1959 March 13 (Box-folder 16: 15)
    - Speech to veterans, typescript, 1959 April (Box-folder 16: 16)
    - Graduation speech, typescript, circa 1959 June (Box-folder 16: 17)
    - Briefing for Congressional visitors, typescript, circa 1960 (Box-folder 16: 18)
    - Speech, "The Challenge of the Profession of Arms," typescript, circa 1960 (Box-folder 16: 19)
    - Speech, MAAG Chiefs Conference, typescript, 1960 April 18 (Box-folder 16: 20)
  - Speeches by others
    - General, typescript, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 16: 21)
    - Lansdale, Col. Edward G., typescript, 1960 (Box-folder 16: 22)
    - Ngo-Dinh-Diem, President, typescript, undated (Box-folder 16: 23)
    - Patton, Gen. George, typescript, undated (Box-folder 16: 24)
    - Taylor, Gen. Maxwell D., typescript, 1955 (Box-folder 16: 25)
    - Vu Nan Mau, South Vietnamese Foreign Minister, typescript, 1960 (Box-folder 16: 26)
    - White, Gen. I. D., typescript, 1955 (Box-folder 16: 27)
- RETIREMENT YEARS FILE, 1960-1980 (Boxes 17-24)
  Biographical material, clippings, correspondence, speeches and writings, and subject file, arranged by physical format. The correspondence file contains detailed descriptions and opinions by Lt. Gen. Williams to friends, colleagues, and family members regarding his service in World War II and Vietnam and American politics in the 1960s.
  - Biographical file (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1980
    - Correspondence lists (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - General
      - Unidentified (Box-folder 17: 4)
      - A-C (Box-folder 17: 5)
      - D-I (Box-folder 17: 6)
      - J-M (Box-folder 17: 7)
      - N-S (Box-folder 17: 8)
      - T-Y (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - Abrams, Maj. Gen. Creighton W., 1962-1972 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - Adams, Lt. Gen. Paul D., 1961 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - Affeldt, Allan Paxton, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - Affeldt, Mr. and Mrs. Dennis, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - Affeldt, Erich Leland, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - Agnew, Spiro, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - Army Magazine, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 18: 8)
    - Beach, Gen. Dwight E., 1965-1966 (Box-folder 18: 9)
    - Beverley, James R., 1961-1966 (Box-folder 18: 10)
    - Boye, F. W., Jr., 1963 (Box-folder 18: 11)
    - Brown, Rothwell Hutton, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 18: 12)
    - Brucker, Mr. and Mrs. Wilbur, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 18: 13)
    - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1963 (Box-folder 18: 14)
    - Bykerk, Norman, 1961-1978 (Box-folder 18: 15)
    - Cagwin, Brig. Gen. Lee G., 1964-1969 (Box-folder 18: 16)
    - Case, Brig. Gen. Charles C., 1964-1969 (Box-folder 18: 17)
    - Casey, Sir Richard, 1968 (Box-folder 18: 18)
    - Center for Strategic Studies, 1964 (Box-folder 18: 19)
    - Chan, Anthony, 1963-1976 (Box-folder 18: 20)
    - Chan, Michael, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 18: 21)
    - Chase, Maj. Gen. Charles H., 1963-1968 (Box-folder 18: 22)
    - Clarke, Gen. Bruce C., 1961-1970 (Box-folder 18: 23)
    - Clayton, Col. George A,., 1963 (Box-folder 18: 24)
    - Coates, Mr. and Mrs. Harry, 1964-1978 (Box-folder 18: 25)
    - Coates, Marsha, 1964-1979 (Box-folder 18: 26)
    - Connor, Lt. Gen. Albert O., 1962-1969 (Box-folder 18: 27)
    - Corley, Brig. Gen. John, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 18: 28)
    - Crawford, Brig. Gen. Joseph, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 18: 29)
    - Croizat, Col. V. J., 1964-1971 (Box-folder 18: 30)
    - Dittmar, Gus C., 1960-1965 (Box-folder 18: 31)
    - Dobol, Command Sgt. Maj. Theodore L.
      - 1962-1965 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - 1965-1977 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Dodd, Thomas, 1965 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - Donnelly, Lt. Col. Ross, 1962-1971 (Box-folder 19: 4)
    - Dul, Col. Peter A., 1961-1964 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - Dunn, Lt. Gen. T. W., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - Duong-Van-Minh, Gen. (Big Minh), 1961 (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - Edwards, Sgt. and Mrs. William, 1963-1976 (Box-folder 19: 8)
    - Erickson, Harold, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - Eschenberg, Brig. Gen. Emil, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 19: 10)
    - Everett, Carl B., 1966-1976 (Box-folder 19: 11)
    - Fair, Col. Felder, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 19: 12)
    - Finn, Col. John M., 1962-1969 (Box-folder 19: 13)
    - Flachsenhar, Capt. John J., 1962-1968 (Box-folder 19: 14)
    - Fraizer, Rachel Merriman, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 19: 15)
    - French, Lt. Col. Jack S., 1964-1965 (Box-folder 19: 16)
    - Fry, Maj. Gen. James C., 1968 (Box-folder 19: 17)
    - Gallagher, Maj. Gen. Philip E., 1966 (Box-folder 19: 18)
    - Garrison, Lloyd R., 1963-1966 (Box-folder 19: 19)
    - Gray, Maj. Gen. David W., 1961-1968 (Box-folder 19: 20)
    - Gregory, Mr. and Mrs. Gene, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 19: 21)
    - Haig, Alexander M., Jr., 1974 (Box-folder 19: 22)
    - Harkins, Gen. Paul D., 1962 (Box-folder 19: 23)
    - Harmony, Maj. Gen. John W., 1970-1979 (Box-folder 19: 24)
    - Harriman, Averell, 1961 (Box-folder 19: 25)
    - Harris, Herbert (Samuel Williams' nephew), 1962-1977 (Box-folder 19: 26)
    - Harris, Ida Ann (Samuel Williams' niece), 1964-1979 (Box-folder 19: 27)
    - Harris, Richard, Jr., 1979 (Box-folder 19: 28)
    - Harris, Robert, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 19: 29)
    - Harris, Mr. and Mrs. Woodson (Samuel Williams' sister, Mary), 1963-1970 (Box-folder 19: 30)
    - Hartshorn, Brig. Gen. Edward S., Jr., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 19: 31)
    - Henderson, Mr. and Mrs. Charles, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 19: 32)
    - Henderson, Ida Williams (Samuel Williams' sister), 1967-1975 (Box-folder 19: 33)
    - Henderson, Mr. and Mrs. Mercer, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 19: 34)
    - Henderson, Teresa Ann, 1976 (Box-folder 19: 35)
    - Henry Regnery Co., 1964 (Box-folder 19: 36)
    - Hilburn, Herbert, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 19: 37)
    - Hill, Mr. and Mrs. Paul, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 19: 38)
    - Horner, Col. Charles T., Jr., 1962-1964 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - Huebner, Lt. Gen. Clarence Ralph, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - Huntington, Col. F. W., 1961-1963 (Box-folder 20: 3)
    - Huynh-Van-Cao, Col., 1961-1966 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - International Water Corporation, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - Jacobson, George D., 1961-1968 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - Jaegher, Father Raymond de, 1961-1979 (Box-folder 20: 7-8)
    - Johnson, Albert S., 1962-1967 (Box-folder 20: 9)
    - Judd, Walter, 1964 (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 1961-1962 (Box-folder 20: 11)
    - Kent, Col. Jim R., 1961-1964 (Box-folder 20: 12)
    - Keuseff, Annette Henderson (Samuel Williams' niece), 1974-1979 (Box-folder 20: 13)
    - Lampert, Maj. Gen. and Mrs. James B., 1961-1978 (Box-folder 20: 14)
    - Lansdale, Edward, 1961-1978 (Box-folder 20: 15)
    - Lasche, Col. Ernest P., 1963-1979 (Box-folder 20: 16)
    - Lawless, Col. Roger E., 1962-1973 (Box-folder 20: 17)
    - Lay, Col. Kenneth E., 1961-1962 (Box-folder 20: 18)
    - Lemberes, Lt. Col. Alexander, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 20: 19)
    - Le-Van-Nhat, Col., 1975 (Box-folder 20: 20)
    - Le-Van-Ty, Gen., 1961-1963 (Box-folder 20: 21)
    - LeVaufre, Henri, 1971 (Box-folder 20: 22)
    - Lindeman, Maj. Gen. Philip F., 1964 (Box-folder 20: 23)
    - Luttichau, Charles V. P. von, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 20: 24)
    - Lynn, Maj. Gen. Otis C., 1978-1980 (Box-folder 20: 25)
    - MacBride, Lt. Col. George, 1964-1978 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - McCullough, John W., 1964-1979 (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - McNeece, Florence, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - MacNeely, Carlton O., 1964-1965 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - Markey, Col. Edward W., 1961-1963 (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - Maroun, Brig. Gen. Autrey, 1962 (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - Mason, Clint, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 21: 7)
    - Merriman, Mr. and Mrs. Lawrence (Samuel Williams' niece), 1964-1979 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - Meyer, Harold J., 1977 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - Moses, Maj. Gen. Lloyd R., 1964-1970 (Box-folder 21: 10)
    - Murray, Ernest J., 1962-1974 (Box-folder 21: 11)
    - Myers, Lt. Gen. Samuel, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 21: 12)
    - Ngo-Dinh-Diem, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 21: 13)
    - Ngo-Dinh-Nhu, Madame, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 21: 14)
    - Nguyen-Dinh-Thuan, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 21: 15)
    - Nguyen-Ngoc-Le, Maj. Gen., 1962 (Box-folder 21: 16)
    - Nilsson, Col. Erwin C., 1960-1978 (Box-folder 21: 17)
    - O'Daniel, Lt. Gen. John W., 1963-1966 (Box-folder 21: 18)
    - Odom, Sgt. George, 1969 (Box-folder 21: 19)
    - Opal, Chester, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 21: 20)
    - Ordoyne, Lucien, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 21: 21)
    - Petty, O. Scott, 1961 (Box-folder 21: 22)
    - Phinney, Gen. Carl, 1961 (Box-folder 21: 23)
    - Plummer, Lt. Col. Frank, 1968 (Box-folder 21: 24)
    - Prado, Lt. Col. Miguel, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 21: 25)
    - Randolph, Mr. and Mrs. Andrew, 1965 (Box-folder 21: 26)
    - Randolph, Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth (Samuel Williams' niece, Rachel), 1964-1979 (Box-folder 21: 27)
    - Rich, Lt. Gen. Charles W. G., 1964-1970 (Box-folder 21: 28)
    - Robb, Col. John E., 1962-1975 (Box-folder 21: 29)
    - Rollins, Maj. Gen. Andy P., 1965-1968 (Box-folder 21: 30)
    - Rostow, Walt W., 1961 (Box-folder 21: 31)
    - Ruggles, Maj. Gen. John F., 1963-1964 (Box-folder 21: 32)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1961 (Box-folder 21: 33)
    - Ryan, Brig. Gen. Ward S., 1966 (Box-folder 21: 34)
    - Seaman, Lt. Gen. Jonathan O., 1965-1966 (Box-folder 21: 35)
    - Seitz, Maj. Gen. Jeff F. R., 1963 (Box-folder 21: 36)
    - Shin, Choi-Duk, Gen., 1962 (Box-folder 21: 37)
    - Shin, Choi-Kuk, Gen., 1964-1966 (Box-folder 21: 38)
    - Shultz, Col. and Mrs. John, 1963-1979 (Box-folder 21: 39)
    - Song, Yo Chan, 1961 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Spear, Mr. and Mrs. Eugene, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - Stann, Col Eugene G., 1964-1965 (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - Stilwell, Maj. Gen. Richard, 1962-1979 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - Strickler, Col. Gilbert, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Stromberg, Brig. Gen. W. W., 1962-1964 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Stump, Adm. Felix
      - 1961-1963 (Box-folder 22: 7)
      - 1963-1965 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Taylor, Maj. Gen. B. Frank, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 22: 9)
    - Taylor, Gen. Maxwell D., 1962-1966 (Box-folder 22: 10)
    - Thai-Quang-Hoang, Maj. Gen., 1961 (Box-folder 22: 11)
    - Thomas, Martin H., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 22: 12)
    - Thompson, H. Keith, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 22: 13)
    - Thompson, William B., 1964-1967 (Box-folder 22: 14)
    - Ton-That-Dinh, Brig. Gen., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 22: 15)
    - Tower, John G., 1964-1971 (Box-folder 22: 16)
    - Townsend, Maj. Gen. Elias Carter, 1961-1972 (Box-folder 22: 17)
    - Tran-Trung-Dung, 1961-1966 (Box-folder 22: 18)
    - Tran-Van-Chuong, 1961 (Box-folder 22: 19)
    - Tran-Van-Don, Gen. and Mrs., 1962-1975 (Box-folder 22: 20)
    - Trudeau, Lt. Gen. Arthur G., 1962 (Box-folder 22: 21)
    - Underwood, Gen. G. V., Jr., 1971 (Box-folder 22: 22)
    - Van Fleet, Gen. James A., 1961-1963 (Box-folder 22: 23)
    - Ward, Col. Nathaniel, III, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 22: 24)
    - Watts, Marvin H., 1961-1968 (Box-folder 22: 25)
    - Wedemeyer, Gen. Albert C., 1961 (Box-folder 22: 26)
    - Wheeler, Gen. Earle G., 1963-1970 (Box-folder 22: 27)
    - White, Gen. I. D., 1961 (Box-folder 22: 28)
    - Whitlow, Robert H., 1972 (Box-folder 22: 29)
    - Williams, Mr. and Mrs. Ed P., Jr. (Samuel Williams' nephew), 1964-1978 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Williams, Mr. and Mrs. Ed P., Sr. (Samuel Williams' brother), 1961-1974 (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Williams, Fred C. (Samuel Williams' brother), 1971-1976 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - Williams, Pauline, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - Williams, Paxton, 1962-1979 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Williams, Viola, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - Witt, Col. D. M., 1964-1969 (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - Wong, Charlotte and Mary, 1962 (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - Wong, Mr. and Mrs. Chiu, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 23: 9)
    - Wong, James Peter, 1963-1978 (Box-folder 23: 10)
    - Wong, Mr. and Mrs. Paul, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 23: 11)
    - Wong, William, 1962-1972 (Box-folder 23: 12)
    - Wong, Mr. and Mrs. William, 1967-1978 (Box-folder 23: 13)
    - Woolfley, Francis A., 1964-1971 (Box-folder 23: 14)
    - Mai-Hu'u-Xuan, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 23: 15)
    - Yates, Eames L., 1969-1972 (Box-folder 23: 16)
  - Speeches and writings
    - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 23: 17)
    - Speech relating to Vietnam, Fort Sill, Oklahoma, typescript, 1961 February 25 (Box-folder 23: 18)
    - Address to the Command and General Staff College, typescript, 1961 March 22 (Box-folder 23: 19)
    - Speech, "Military Assistance Program," typescript, 1961 April (Box-folder 23: 20)
    - Speech, "Personal Reflections on Leadership," typescript, 1961 May 8 (Box-folder 23: 21)
    - "Reflections on Leadership," Military Review, printed copy, 1961 October (Box-folder 23: 22)
    - Speech, "Armistice Day, Then and Now," 90th Infantry Division Veterans of World War II, Texoma, Oklahoma, typescript, 1961 November 11 (Box-folder 23: 23)
    - Speech, "Vietnam," American Legion, typescript, 1963 December 4 (Box-folder 23: 24)
    - Speech, "Experiences in Vietnam," Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, typescript, 1964 (Box-folder 23: 25)
    - Speech, "Personal Observations of Certain Foreign Military Personnel," First Officers' Training Camp Association, San Antonio, Texas, typescript, 1964 May 2 (Box-folder 23: 26)
    - "Why U.S. Is Losing in Vietnam: An Inside Story," U.S. News and World Report, interview, printed copy, 1964 November 9 (Box-folder 23: 27)
    - "Vietnam," co-authored with Edward Hymoff, typescript, 1965 (Box-folder 23: 28)
    - Speech, "Facts about Vietnam and Its People," Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, typescript, 1965 (Box-folder 23: 29)
    - Speech, "Power for Peace: A Legacy of Liberty," Kiwanis Club, Denton, Texas, typescript, 1965 May 11 (Box-folder 23: 30)
    - Speech, "Vietnam," Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, typescript, 1965 May 14 (Box-folder 23: 31)
    - "Peace at any Price," typescript, 1966 (Box-folder 23: 32)
    - Speech, "Vietnam," First Officers Training Camp Association, typescript, 1967 May 6 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - Speech, "Veterans' Day: 1968," typescript (Box-folder 24: 2)
    - "Memorabilia," typescript, 1969 October - 1970 March (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - Oral history interview, typescript, 1970 (Box-folder 24: 4)
      Interview was conducted on 18 August 1970, under the auspices of the Project Corona Harvest Oral History Program, and reviewed and edited by Williams on 19 October 1970. Includes declassified records returned to file after February 2016 release by Hoover.
  - Subject file
    - Laos, 1961 (Box-folder 24: 5)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 24: 6)
    - Sun Tze, 1960 April 4 (Box-folder 24: 7)
      Report by Commander Tran-Van-Chon, typescript.
    - United States
      - American Security Council (Box-folder 24: 8)
      - Army
        - Capital Military Assistance Command (CMAC) (Box-folder 24: 9)
        - Command and General Staff College (Box-folder 24: 10)
        - Reserved Officers Training Corp (ROTC) (Box-folder 24: 11)
        - West Point (Box-folder 24: 12)
    - Vietnam
      - General (Box-folder 24: 13)
      - Duong-Van-Minh (Big Minh) and Tran-Van-Minh (Little Minh) (Box-folder 24: 14)
      - Erickson, H. F., "The Incredible Buddhist Affair," typescript, undated (Box-folder 24: 15)
      - Free Democratic Party of Vietnam, "White Paper on Ngo Dinh Diem's Regime," printed copy, 1961 (Box-folder 24: 16)
      - National Broadcasting Corporation, Meet the Press: America's Press Conference of the Air, printed transcripts of interviews, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 24: 17)
        Includes Senator J.W. Fulbright, Gen. Maxwell D. Taylor, and Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr.
      - Pan, Dr. Stephen C. Y. (Box-folder 24: 18)
      - United States Department of State, "A Threat to the Peace: North Vietnam's Effort to Conquer South Vietnam," printed copy, 1961 (Box-folder 24: 19)
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1955-1961 (Tape cabinet)
  9 sound tape reels relating to military operations.
  - United States Department of Defense press conference, 1958 (Tape 1)
  - "Military Assistance Program," speech, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas, 1961 March 22 (Tape 2-3)
  - CINCPAC briefing, 1955 (Tape 4-8)
  - Military Assistance Advisory Group briefing, 1957 May 31 (Tape 9)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1941-1961, undated (Photo file, Oversize photo file)
  104 prints / 9 envelopes.
  - 21 miscellaneous prints, undated (Envelope A)
    Includes 9 prints of Father Raymond de Jaegher, 2 prints of Ngo-Dinh-Nhu, and 1 print of Gen. Omar Bradley, as well as 1 print of Lt. Gen. Williams on the steps of Pershing House, Fort Sam Houston, with other former commanding generals of the Fourth U.S. Army (1972).
  - 10 portrait prints of Lt. Gen. Samuel T. Williams, 1941-1954 (Envelope B)
  - 5 prints depicting Lt. Gen. Williams' command in Germany, 1946-1950 (Envelope C)
  - 5 prints depicting the 26th Infantry Regiment, undated (Envelope D)
  - 28 prints depicting Lt. Gen. Williams' Command in Korea and Japan, 1952-1954 (Envelope E)
    Includes 8 prints of Syngman Rhee and 8 prints of Gen. Maxwell Taylor.
  - 7 prints depicting Lt. Gen. Williams' command at Fort Sam Houston, 1955 (Envelope F)
  - 16 prints depicting Lt. Gen. Williams as Chief of MAAG, 1955-1960 (Envelope G)
    Includes 5 prints of Pres. Ngo-Dinh-Diem, 1 print of Amb. Eldridge Durbrow, 2 prints of Gen. Le-Van-Ty, 1 print of Gen. DUong-Van-Minh (Big Minh), and 2 prints of Sec. Wilbur Brucker.
  - 10 prints of Lt. Gen. Williams' visit to West Point, 1961 (Envelope H)
  - 3 miscellaneous prints, undated (Envelope mI)
    Includes 1 print of Gen. Le-Van-Ty, Maj. Gen. Ton-That-Dinh, and Lt. Gen. Samuel T. Williams.